uh welcome
everyone uh that is the question Whom
Shall I Fear when God is on our
side uh we have no one to
fear uh let the people say
amen so today we have a very special
subject uh the subject is dealing with
the teach teaching of
Hellfire and um there's a lot of
misunderstanding about this subject uh
today we're going to be uh we're going
to be getting into the word of God we're
going to be doing a a Bible study and
we're going to look at what the Bible
has to say about this subject and again
I want to encourage you uh to to to
share this
link because uh what we are about to
learn
uh will be
lifechanging uh particularly for people
who have been fearful of this subject uh
we're going to see some really powerful
some really amazing things now um put a
one in the chat if you are ready for
this subject put a one in the chat if
you are ready to hear and learn and
understand about this subject and I'm
going to say something okay at at
various times in this message you're
going to hear me say something that if
you've never heard the subject before
it's going to throw you for Loop um hang
in there keep
listening um I promise you this is all
going to come together and you will have
an understanding of this subject like
never before so with that said um we're
g to pray and then we're going to get
into the message again start sharing
this link people you know that are
confused about this subject that maybe
have turned away from God because of
this subject um the the the the subject
of an eternally burning hell I need you
to share this link let's pray and get
into this okay let's do that now
Heavenly Father um bless us Lord as we
open your word I pray that you would
give wisdom give understanding and above
all Lord uh bring
conviction set our hearts on fire is our
prayer in Jesus name amen and
amen so we're going to go to our screen
and uh the subject the title of the
message today is this
fireproof the truth about
Hellfire once again fire prooof the
truth about Hellfire
so the first thing that that I want you
uh to notice here and and and by the way
um this teach
teaching the incorrect teaching of this
subject has done more to turn people
away from God than any other subject
hands
down if God is a god of
love how does
that how does that measure up with this
idea that God Burns people in Hell
forever so that's a question we're going
to be tackling and and the first thing
that I want you to understand is that uh
uh people typically put the word the
words
Hellfire
together but what I need you to
understand is that
hell and fire are two different
things
hell and fire are two different things
and so what we want to do is we want to
first talk talk about hell according to
the Old
Testament what is hell that's a question
we have right now what is hell so let's
go to the scripture the Bible says in
Psalms chapter 9 and verse
17 the wicked shall be turned into hell
and All Nations that forget God now this
seems like a pretty
standard understanding of hell right
that the that hell is designated for the
wicked now put a one in the
chat if you believe that hell is
designated for the wicked one in the
chat if you if you think hell's
designated for the wicked put that one
if you if you think something else don't
anything um this is a trick question by
the way because I want you to
notice that
hell is not only designated for the
wicked Pastor what are you talking about
please note with
me according to Psalm 16 and verse1 the
Bible says for thou will not leave my
soul in Hell neither wil thou suffer
thine Holy One to see corruption
according to this text which we will see
is a prophetic text talking about
someone very
specific the text there says for thou
will not leave my soul whoever that my
is that my that's that that this is
referring to is someone that's
righteous thou will not leave my soul in
in Hell well Pastor how can you say that
the
righteous that the that hell is also
that the righteous are also in Hell how
can you say that well let's let's go to
the Book of Genesis chapter 37 and we're
going to read something that Jacob
himself
says J in Genesis chapter 37:34 and
Jacob rent his clothes and put sackcloth
upon his loin and mourned for his son
many days speaking about Joseph and all
his sons and all his daughters rose up
to comfort him but he refused to be
comforted and said for I will go down
into the grave unto my son morning thus
his father wept for him the text says
that Jacob is speaking here and he says
I will go down into the grave now here's
what I need y'all to
understand this word for grave is the
very same word in the Old Testament that
is used for hell put one in the chat if
you understand that the word here for
grave is the very same word Shield that
is used for
hell now let me ask a question Jacob
would you consider him righteous or
Wicked was J is Jacob going is Jacob was
Jacob a righteous man or was he a wicked
man he was a righteous man amen so if he
was a righteous man what is he
doing talking about I'm going to hell
hell I will go down to Hell mourning my
son well when you understand that
according to the Old
Testament
hell is the
grave then things begin to make a little
bit more sense
ah so that means everybody's going to
hell
put a one in the chat if you understand
what I just
said while you're while you're
contemplating what I just said wait what
did the pastor just say let me just give
you a little bit more let me just give
you a few more verses Psalm 30:2 oh Lord
my God I Cried unto thee and thou Hast
healed me oh Lord thou Hast brought up
my soul from the grave thou has kept me
alive that I should not go down to the
pit so the pit is the same thing as the
grave and once again the Hebrew word for
grave here is the same word used to
describe hell therefore what the Old
Testament is showing
us is that
hell is a
place that both the righteous and the
wicked go why is that because hell is
simply the grave now please note what I
said
earlier
Hellfire is something
different from Hell please keep that
thought in
mind Hell Fire is something different
from Hell according to the Old Testament
we are simply seeing here that hell is
is the grave and the grave is where
everybody
goes everybody's going to
hell now that sounds jarring it sounds
like what in the world is the pastor
talking about but when we understand
that hell is not a place designated for
the wicked hell is a place designated
for all who die then oh okay I get that
now I understand stand that now let me
just make it a little bit
clearer according to Psalm 89 and verse
84 the Bible says what man is he that
liveth and shall not see Death Shall he
deliver his soul from the hand of the
Grave guess what the word is that is
used for grave here it is the word hell
let's read that again
what man is he that liveth and shall not
see death in other words what man is he
that liveth and shall not go to the
Grave shall not die shall not go to the
pit or from what we
understand shall not go to where
everyone
hell why because according to the Old
Testament hell is simply the grave
hell sh is simply the grave it is where
people go when they die and how do we
know this well if you go back with me to
the Book of Genesis chapter 3 you'll
remember that after Adam sins and of
course the Bible tells us that the wages
of sin is what the wages of sin
is death yeah so when Adam and Eve
sinned notice what the Bible
says God is pronouncing death upon them
and the Bible says in Genesis 3:19 in
the sweat of thy face shalt thou eat
bread till you return to the
wear where was Adam going to return
to return to the ground why for out of
it thou was taken for dust you are and
unto dust shall you return so let me ask
you a question when Adam died where did
he go put it in the chat for me please
where did Adam go when he died and I
don't want the word dust either I don't
want the word ground either tell
me in light of the subject we are
speaking about when Adam died where did
he go yes Lynette Adam went to hell to
the ground to the Grave to the dust
that's where Adam went and and and
because watch
this because the Bible says wherefore as
by one man sin entered into the world
and death by sin so death passed upon
all men for that all have sinned what
the Bible is trying to tell us is that
all
have sinned and therefore all will go to
the Grave or will go to
hell put a one in the chat if y'all are
with me so
far hell is not the meaning that many
have put on it as this is a special
place for the wicked no hell is the
place where all go because of sin the
wicked and the
righteous because hell was simply
another term for the grave it's simply
another term for
death so now now that we understand that
and by the
way the wicked will be destroyed by make
no mistake about it but we have to see
this in its actual truth we have to
understand this how it actually unfolds
not what Hollywood says and not what
popular teaching says we need to see
this from it from straight from the word
of
God not not just a text here and then
see this text says this and that's the
whole teaching no we're going to build a
systematic approach to this subject so
that you can see and we're going to see
this very clearly you won't have any
questions by the grace of God all right
so here's our next here's our next
question as we're dealing with this
subject you w to have any questions when
this is done because by the grace of God
you will
understand this Truth for what it is
okay
so what are the
current conditions of
Hell fair
question yeah fair question if if all go
to hell meaning all go to the Grave then
the question is what is the current
condition of hell what are the current
living conditions of
Hell how How would we how would we
describe the living conditions in
Hell well here's the answer the answer
is there are no living conditions in
Hell Pastor what are you saying well
let's check it
out according to Ecclesiastes chapter 9
and verse 10 the Bible says whatsoever
thy hand findeth to do do it with thy
might for there is no work no nor
device nor
knowledge nor
wisdom
in
the what
everybody in the grave
wither thou now who's the thou
there who who is the thou there is the
thou talking to people who typically
read the
Bible so the thou is talking to people
who would read the Bible then we know
that the thou there at least represents
the
righteous God says the place that you
are
going hell there's no knowledge
there there's no
understanding there's no there's no
feeling there's no emotion there's
nothing there it's just darkness
here's how job described it job
described it this way here's what he
said and why Dost thou not pardon my
transgression and take away my iniquity
for now shall I sleep in the
dust Thou shalt seek me in the morning
but I shall not be so job describes this
state of being in hell as a sleep
so uh Ecclesiastes says you know nothing
there's no knowledge there's no wisdom
there's no device you can't do anything
there you're not sitting there in the
grave like man this is boring no it says
there is no knowledge there and job says
it's like you're
sleeping that is the
current
condition of hell are y'all with me so
far we're just building we're just
building the subject so far we're just
seeing what the the Bible has to say
we've we've we we've now seen that hell
is something different from Hell Fire
from the punishment of the wicked there
is a condition of Hell which is simply
the
grave
death going back to the dust of the
ground both the righteous and the wicked
are in Hell meaning they're all in the
grave They're All Dead those who have
gone before us they are all in
hell right
now so far so good then let's move to
our next question which is this what
will Jesus do for those in
hell what will Jesus do for those in
Hell well here's a qu here's the
answer Jesus is going to do something
not for everybody in hell but only for
some in
hell now remember the current condition
of hell is sleep death there's no
knowledge there's no device we've just
gotten that from the scriptures I didn't
make that up it's it's right there you
can't manipulate those words you can't
no there's nothing there so so so we
know that both the wicked and the
righteous are currently in
Hell asleep no no knowledge no wisdom
now you say what about this verse in the
New Testament we'll get there we're
moving our way slowly through the word
of God so let's see what Jesus what the
Bible says Jesus will do for those in
Hell notice Hosea chapter
13:14 here it says I will Ransom them
from the power of the Grave stop right
there no no let's keep reading let's
keep reading I will redeem them from
death oh death I will be thy plagues oh
grave I will be thy destruction
repentance shall be hid from my eyes so
the text is telling us that even though
the righteous are currently in Hell
Jesus has a plan to Ransom them from the
power of the Grave from Death From Hell
put a two in the chat if y'all are with
me so far Jesus says even though the
righteous are there I'm going to Ransom
them they're not their
suffering because the Bible says that
they have no knowledge no wisdom no
understanding there's nothing they can
do in there they're asleep the the
righteous are asleep just like the
wicked in
hell do you know how tormenting it is
how traumatic we talked about trauma
this morning in the Sabbath School do
you know how much trauma the teaching of
an eternally burn hell where people die
and go right now they go there right now
so if you know that your loved one
didn't die in the Lord you're thinking
right now right now as we speak they are
burning in hell do you know how mentally
traumatic that teaching is when what
we've seen in the word of God is
no the righteous and the wicked are all
in hell but they're all sleeping
in other words hell is not yet Hell
Fire it's just
hell are y'all with me it's just hell
right now and I know for many of you
watching you're already jumping to
Lazarus in the but just hold on I'm
getting there hold on wait we're getting
there we just need to get a firm
understanding of what the Old Testament
teaches about hell okay so we've already
seen that there's a plan to Ransom the
righteous From Hell from the grave
question is how will Jesus accomplish
this how will he accomplish this
ransoming from the grave how will he
accomplish this redeeming of the
righteous from the grave well he
accomplished it through the cross
somebody somebody needs to say Amen
somebody needs to say amen he
accomplished it through the cross and I
want you to notice on the day of
Pentecost Peter is
speaking a and Peter says this to the
people listening
on he says in Acts 2 verse 25 for David
speaking concerning
him I foresaw the lord always before me
he is on my right hand that I should not
be moved therefore did my heart rejoice
and my tongue was glad moreover also my
flesh shall Rest In Hope now watch the
next words because thou will not leave
my soul in Hell neither Willl thou
suffer thine Holy One to see
corruption thou has made known to me the
ways of of Life Thou shalt make me full
of joy with thy countenance now watch
Peter's commentary on this men and
Brethren let me freely speak unto you of
of the patriarch
David that he is both both dead and
buried and his supper is with us unto
this day in other words what Peter is
saying is
this y'all know who wrote this right
y'all know who said this right David
said this but I need you to understand
that David was not speaking about
himself how do we know that because
David is still
dead he is still in the grave meaning he
is still where
everyone where did the text say you will
not leave my soul in
where so come on y'all David the man
after God's Own Heart where is he right
now according to Peter and This is 40
days 50 days after the crucifixion and
resurrection of Christ David is in
where come
on he's in
Hell David the man after God's Own heart
is in in hell right
now why is Peter mentioning this 50 days
after the resurrection of Jesus notice
what it goes on to say therefore verse
30 therefore being a prophet and knowing
that God had sworn an oath to him that
of the fruit of his loins according to
the flesh he would raise up Christ to
sit on his throne he seeing this before
spake of the resurrection of Christ
that his soul was
not
what wait a minute wait a
minute
Jesus went to
where come on come on you guys I need
you to put this in the
chat when Jesus died where did he
go put it in the chat
put it in the chat Yes Y'all Jesus went
to hell and now you understand that that
whole teaching of Jesus going into
something called Purgatory is absolutely
false it is not what the Bible is
talking
about Jesus went to hell simply means
Jesus went to the Grave on our behalf he
died and was buried in fact remember
when Jonah was cast Over the the the the
boat and the Bible says that Jonah
speaking says for three days and three
nights he was in the belly of
Hell Ah that's why Jesus said as Jonah
was in the belly of the fish for three
days and three nights so shall the son
of man be in the heart bew in the heart
heart of the Earth where is hell it's
the heart of the earth meaning listen to
me meaning hell is not somewhere in the
earth people don't die and now they're
going to this underworld called hell no
it's the
grave Jesus went to the Grave on our
behalf and because of his
resurrection he overcame and opened the
gates come on y'all
he opened the gates of death and
hell in order to Ransom the
righteous are y'all with
me when the Bible says in second Peter
that Jesus went to
hell it's talking about the grave
when it talk when it talks about it was
by that spirit that he preached to
Spirits in prison in the days of Noah
it's not telling us that in the that
that when Jesus went Jesus went to the
grave and somehow preached to a select
group of people who lived in Noah's day
no no no it's simply saying that the
same spirit that Rose Jesus from the
grave is the same spirit that was there
in the days of Noah when when people
were rebellious upon Earth it was that
same spirit that was striving with men
for 120 years it is not saying that
Jesus went down to this underworld where
there's a whole bunch of people and he
preached to them after their probation
had closed beloved when you die that's
it you're either saved or lost there's
no second chance after
death but I
digress we're simply seeing here that
Jesus has a plan to Ransom the wicked
from hell but in order to do that he had
to go to hell himself he had to go to
the Grave himself he had to carry his
cross to Calvary and die on our behalf
and then through his own power and the
power of his father break open the gates
of the Grave to give man hope and to let
man see that eternal life is in fact a
possibility so with that in mind we now
have another question when are they
ransomed from hell when are the
Righteous ransomed from
hell
when according to 1 Corinthians chapter
15:51 please
note Paul writing says this behold I
show you a mystery we shall not all
sleep but we shall all be changed notice
he calls death asleep just like the Old
Testament nothing's changed from the old
to the new Paul says we shall not all
sleep meaning not everybody's going to
die they're going to be some people who
are
alive and translated when Jesus comes
again that's what he's saying but notice
what he says notice what he goes on to
say in a moment in the twinkling of an
eye at the last Trump at the last Trump
at the last Trump for the trumpet shall
sound and the dead shall be raised in
corruptible and we shall be changed for
this corruptible must put on
incorruption and this Mortal must put on
immortality so when this corruptible
shall have put on incorruption and this
Mortal shall have put on immortality
then shall be brought to pass the V the
saying that is written death is
swallowed up in Victory oh death where
is thy sting oh grave oh
hell where is thy Victory so again again
the question is when are the Righteous
ransomed from
Hell the answer is at the last Trump not
when they die when they die they go into
hell they go into the grave they are
ransomed from the grave at the second
coming of Jesus this is why Isaiah 26:19
says this thy dead men shall live
together with my dead body shall they
arise this is resurrection y'all awaken
sing ye that dwell in the dust ye that
dwell in the dust for thy do is as the D
of the herbs and the Earth shall cast
out her dead when will the earth cast
out her dead not when the not when the
righteous die it is when Jesus comes
again that's when the Earth casts out
her dead that's when the grave that's
when hell is
robbed is robbed from her hell's
subjects that's when the
grave is
emptied that's when hell is emptied look
at how Daniel uh chter 12 verse2 puts it
many of them that sleep in the dust of
the Earth shall awake so some to
everlasting life and some to shame and
everlasting contempt so so far oh here's
what we're seeing you guys this is being
laid out very
simply that all die all go to hell but
the righteous will be redeemed from Hell
the condition of hell right
now is that it is not burning there is
no fire in hell right now it's just the
grave
I'm going somewhere with this please
follow along especially if you have
never heard this before because I
promise you this is going to bring such
peace to your soul about the character
of
God
so Jesus redeems or ransoms the
righteous from the From Hell from the
grave at the second coming once again
John chapter 5: 28 Marvel not at this
for the hour is coming in which all that
are in the graves
that is in Hell shall hear his voice and
shall come forth they that have done
good unto the resurrection of life and
they that have done evil unto the
resurrection of damnation so now we are
seeing that according to Jesus there are
two resurrections there is the
resurrection of life and there is the
resurrection of damnation so I need you
to catch this y'all there are
two resurrections one for for the
righteous one for the wicked let's keep
going 1 Thessalonians chap
4:16 just to affirm for the Lord himself
shall descend from heaven with a shout
with the voice of the Archangel and with
the Trump of God that's that last Trump
and the dead in Christ shall rise rise
where rise from the grave rise where
rise from hell that's where they are
being raised up from from then we which
are alive and remain meaning we never
died those that are alive when Christ
comes again the second time shall be
caught up together with them in the
clouds to meet the Lord in the air so
shall we ever be with the Lord you can
see very clearly beloved that this this
does not happen at death it happens at
Resurrection the righteous are not in
heaven right now if they were why would
Jesus be coming back to get them to take
them to
heaven and I know some of you already
thinking oh well the soul and the spirit
you need to go back and see the previous
message that speaks about what happens
to a person when they die I'm not going
to do that in this message I just need
you to know that I've addressed this
just go back and look at the message
right before this there's a playlist
it's called the share the truth playlist
just go back this is number four I
believe number four or number five in
the playlist just go back and look at
the one right before this because this
one is a followup to what happens to a
person when they die okay so having
shared that I need you to see something
now in the Book of Revelation chapter 20
this brings it all together for us I
want you to note Revelation 20 verse1
and I saw an angel come down from heaven
having the key at the bottomless pit and
a great chain in his hand and he laid
hold on the Dragon that old serpent
which is the devil and Satan and bound
him a thousand years and cast him into
the bottomless pit and shut him up and
set a seal upon him that he should
deceive the Nations no more till the
Thousand Years should be fulfilled and
after that he must be loose a little
season so this is Satan being bound for
a thousand years now please watch
this and I saw Thrones verse four and I
saw Thrones and they sat upon them and
judgment was given unto them and I saw
the soul of them that were beheaded for
the witness of Jesus and for the word of
God and which had not worshiped the
Beast neither his image neither had
received his Mark upon their foreheads
or in their hands and they lived and
reigned with Christ a thousand years but
the rest of the Dead lived not again
until the thousand years were
finished this is the
first
resurrection blessed and holy is he that
has part in the First
Resurrection on such the second death
has no power but they shall be Priests
of God and of Christ and shall reign
with him a thousand years
okay so let me break this down just for
a
moment when Jesus comes
again what we just read is that there
will be a resurrection of the righteous
and that will happen at the beginning of
this 1,000 year
period the rest of the Dead meaning the
wicked remain in hell so let let's let's
let's let's kind of like put this
together
okay because of
Adam all go to the Grave all die all go
to hell but
Jesus has a plan to redeem all who would
like to be redeemed
From Hell from the grave Jesus came into
this world and himself went to hell the
grave died on our
behalf are you with me to open up the
gates of
hell however they're still captives
there because he doesn't Ransom them
until he comes again the second time
which is what is the resurrection it is
the resurrection of the righteous
remember P Jesus said there's going to
be a resurrection of the righteous and
then there will be those who experience
the resurrection of damnation now we
know ah the resurrection of damnation is
the one that happens at the end of the
10,00 years so at the beginning of the
1,000 years all the righteous are
redeemed from Hell meaning at that point
hell is now only occupied by the wicked
put a one in the chat if y'all catch
what I'm saying
hell is now only occupied by the wicked
now so watch this it is it was the death
of Jesus that redeemed all who accepted
the death of Christ were
redeemed from
hell are we good just trying to build a
case here okay doesn't Pretend This is a
court and we're just trying to build a
case to defend or to expose
this false teaching of what is popularly
known as an eternally burning hell okay
so now the question is
remember Psalm 20 I mean Revelation 26
blessed and holy is he that has part in
the First Resurrection on such the
second death has no power so the second
death is for the cursed the second death
is for the cursed and the question now
becomes what is the second death what is
the second death now this is going to
bring it all together for you guys watch
are yall ready for this put a one in the
chat if you're ready for this check out
the second
death this is happening at the end of
the 10,000 years notice what the Bible
says and the Sea gave up the dead which
were in it who would that be who are the
dead that are in the
sea and death and Hell delivered up the
dead which were in them who are all
these people that are being delivered up
here who are they they are the wicked
they are the ones that rejected Christ's
offer to be ransomed from the grave are
you with me they didn't want Christ They
didn't accept his death in their behalf
so there's no Escape From Hell for them
so so they don't get to go in the first
resurrection they have to stay in hell
they have no knowledge they have no
wisdom there's nothing there in in it
for the 10,000 years the wicked dead are
in Hell the righteous are in heaven let
me rephrase this the reason why there is
peace for a thousand years upon the
Earth is not because there are nations
that are like hey you know what we're
you know we're all happy now no no no no
no the nations of the righteous are in
heaven with Jesus 4,000 years the
nations of the wicked are dead on the
earth they are in hell no knowledge no
wisdom no understanding there's no one
on the earth except Satan he is bound
here on this Earth with no one attempt
for a thousand years he can't temp the
wicked because they're dead they have no
knowledge they have no understanding
that's why it is only at the end of the
1,000 years when the wicked are
resurrected that Satan gathers them to
fight against God
why can't he tell the righteous because
they're in heaven they've been redeemed
from hell they're in heaven with Christ
for a thousand years so let's go back to
the text watch this the sea gave up the
dead which were in them and death and
Hell delivered up the dead which were in
them and they were judged every man
according to their works so this is the
second death watch this and death in
hell were
cast into the Lake of Fire this is the
second death and whosoever was not found
written in the Book of Life was cast
into the Lake of Fire do y'all
understand this this is where Hell Fire
becomes a
reality do you get
this hell is not burn the reason we know
hell can't be burning now is that it
would make no sense to cast a burning
Place into a lake of fire if the place
is already
burning the the second death is when a
hell begins to
burn are y'all with
me the second death is when so the first
death put it like this there are many
different ways to die the first death
you can die the F the first death from
an accident you can die the first death
from sickness from illness you can die
the first death from all kinds of
different there's a million ways to die
but in the second death there's only one
way that the wicked die and it is
Through
Fire hell is not burning now according
to Revelation 20 hell is not set on fire
on
until the end of the 1,000
years and it's called Hell Fire for a
reason this watch this y'all because
it's good news so when we say house fire
what does that
mean house fire would mean that the fire
is Burning Down The House a forest fire
would mean the fire is burning down the
forest
so what is hellfire
y'all what is
hellfire Hellfire is God burning down
Hellfire it is God destroying
death the only reason that there is hell
is because Adam sinned in the beginning
God does not want a universe with hell
God doesn't want a universe of people
dying so he is ultimately going to
destroy death and hell and he doesn't
want you to be in it when he does it
y'all not feeling me
man God is love he's trying to find a
way to redeem everybody from Hell before
he burns it up however there are some
who who are like nah I'm okay I don't
need Jesus and as a result of
that as a result of that when God
destroys hell when God destroys the
grave when God destroys
death he must destroy them
too yes there is no place Sean in the
new world for hell and for death and so
God is seeking to destroy that entire
system because sin will never rise again
and if sin never rises again there is no
need for death and Hell
so the whole purpose of the Gospel is to
try to redeem as many people from
Hell God is trying to say okay
everyone's got to die everyone's got to
go to hell but there is a plan I can
redeem you from that hell if you simply
accept what I did for you at the
cross are y'all following this
is this making sense put a seven in the
chat if your hearts are burning right
now put a seven in the chat if this is
making sense to you right now I need you
to see this how you doing that I need
you to see this so so the Bible
says and the Sea gave up the dead which
were in it and death and Hell delivered
up the dead which were in them so the
question is where are they where are the
wicked being delivered up
to where are the wicked being delivered
up
to the answer is actually in the very
same chapter the Bible says in
Revelation 20 when a thousand years are
expired Satan shall be loosed out of his
prison and shall go out to deceive the
Nations which are in the four quarters
of the earth Gog and MOG that means the
whole entire Wicked World because all
the righteous are in heaven and the
wicked are on the earth now they're
resurrected they're about to be judged
by God and destroyed but before this
Satan gathers them one final time for
one final assault as the city of God is
coming down out of Heaven at the end of
the 10,000 years to set up its new place
on Earth the wicked who have who who are
on the Earth are seeing the city come
down and they're going to attempt to
take it and then God sets up his
judgment right there they can't take it
watch this it says in verse 8 they shall
go out he shall go out to deceive the
Nations which are in the four quarters
of the earth go and made go to gather
them to to the battle the number of whom
is at the sand of the sea and they went
upon the breath of the earth and
compassed the camp of the Saints about
the Beloved City that same city that
John saw coming down as a bride adorned
for her husband the New Jerusalem coming
down and fire came down from God out of
heaven and devoured them so let me break
this down for
you where are the wicked
devoured they are devoured right upon
the face of the Earth right upon the
breath of the earth I need you to
understand this guys the place where the
wicked will be
destroyed the place where Hell Fire
begins is on this
Earth let me paint this picture for
you the Earth became
hell when When J when when when when
Adam sinned the Earth literally became
hell you die you go into
it the planet became a burial ground
hell the planet is hell y'all not feel
the planet is hell if you just start
digging all you're gonna see is Hell
dead dead dead death everywhere in the
earth so so Jesus at the second coming
what does he do he pulls all the
righteous Out of
Hell the righteous go to be with him for
1,000 years in heaven while the while
Earth is just hell it's the holding
ground of just the wicked now remember
what was Jesus trying to do he was
trying to rid the entire Earth he was
trying to rid he was trying to take
everybody out of hell but there are some
who were like no we don't want Jesus
so they had to stay in hell now at the
end of the 10,000 years and and we're
going to do a whole another sermon on
why the righteous go to heaven with
Christ for a thousand years what are
they doing there for the Thousand Years
while the wicked are dead upon the Earth
that's a whole another sermon whole
another uh uh truth part of the truth
series
however it is at the end of the 10,000
years when Jesus comes back what is he
going to do he's going to turn hell into
fire
he's going to burn hell up what is that
hell it's the entire Earth that's why
the Bible says in Revelation chapter 20
or 21 I saw a new Heaven and a new Earth
for the first Heaven and the first Earth
Earth were passed away why were they
passed away because it is the passing
away of hell and death
here's how the last book in the Old
Testament put it just in case you think
well the Old Testament was teaching
something different no no no no no no
yes Pauline text I'm going to right
now Malachi 4 verse1 the last book of
the Old Testament the last chapter says
this for behold the day cometh that
shall burn as an oven and all the proud
y all that do wickedly shall be stubble
and the day that cometh shall burn them
up say the Lord of hosts that it shall
leave them neither root nor Branch but
unto you that fear my name shall the son
of righteousness arise with healing in
his wings and you shall go forth and
grow up as calves of the stall and you
shall tread down the wicked for they
shall be ashes Under The Souls of your
feet in the day that I do this say the
Lord so where are The Souls of the feet
of the Saints at the end of time on this
Earth where are the ashes of the Wicked
on this
Earth this Earth will become Hell
Fire And once the fire fires has have
cleansed this Earth God then brings New
Jerusalem to rest on a newly recreated
planet
Earth one where there will be no death
no sorrow no crying no
pain come on we're almost there you guys
psalm 37:9 for evildoers shall be cut
off but those that wait upon the Lord
shall inherit the earth for yet a little
while and the wicked shall not be yay
Thou shalt diligent diligently consider
his place and it shall not be but the
meek shall inherit the earth and and
shall Delight themselves in the
abundance of Peace in other words
Beloved the wicked will cease they are
they are burnt up in the fires now I'm
I'm getting to this point I need you to
really follow me closely with this all
right just follow
listen Deuteronomy 33:22 this is the
first time that the words hell and fire
are used in the same verse in the whole
Bible God speaking says for a fire is
kindled in mine anger and shall burn
unto the lowest hell and shall consume
the Earth with her increase and set on
fire The Fountains the foundations of
the mountains the very first time that
the Bible talks about the fires of hell
it says it it's going to destroy the
Earth what is taught in the Old
Testament is taught in the New Testament
nothing new here it's the same thing
okay let's keep moving Psalm 11:6 upon
the wicked shall he Reign snares fire
and brimstone and a horrible Tempest
this shall be the portion of the cup
same teaching Psalm 50 verse three Our
God shall come and shall not keep
silence a fire shall devour before him
and it shall be very tempestuous round
about him same thing Psalm 97:3 a fire
goeth before him and burneth up his
enemies round about same thing Isaiah
47:14 behold they shall be a stubble the
fire shall burn them they shall not
deliver themselves from the power of the
flame same thing Isaiah 66:15 for behold
the Lord will come with fire and with
his chariots like a whirlwind to render
his anger with Fury and his rebuke with
the flames of fire same thing Mark 9
verse 43 for if thine hand offend thee
cut it off it is better for thee to
enter into life mean than having two
hands to go into hell into the fire that
shall never be quenched now let me just
pause right here for a second because
this text in Mark chapter 9 verse 43
tells us
clearly that the wicked are bodily
destroyed in in Hell
Fire it's not a spirit in
hell you are but the wicked will be
bodily destroyed in hell and that's the
purpose of the fire the fire is going to
destroy that's why Jesus said that they
will go H with both hands into
hell and Jesus is speaking specifically
of the hell that will be on fire at the
very end of
time we're going to break this
down we're going to break this text down
but but I'mma come back to this so what
I want you to note thus far is that the
W the wicked will be physically
destroyed in hell that
hell is only set on fire at the end of
the 1,000 years and it happens upon the
face of the Earth Mark CH Matthew
chapter 13:37 illustrates this again he
answered and said unto them he that sewe
the good seed is the son of man the
field is the world the good seed are the
children of the Kingdom but the tears
are the children of the wicked one the
enemy that sold them is a devil and the
Harvest is the end of the world and the
reapers are the angels as therefore the
tears are gathered and burned in the
fire so shall it be
now so shall it be now no no no no no so
shall it be in the end of this world the
son of man shall send forth his angels
and they Shall Gather out of his kingdom
all things that offend and them and them
which do iniquity and shall cast them
into a furnace of fire and there shall
be wailing and nashing of teeth in other
words like there'll be body parts it's
not spiritual teeth it's actual teeth if
you're wailing it's because you have
eyes the wicked will literally be put
into or will be cast into into fire and
this we see happens at the end of the
world it's not happening now
how many people have turned away from
God because they're like how can God be
a god of love and yet he's burning
continuously my loved one who I know
wasn't
saved or who I believe wasn't saved
they're burning in hell right now the
Bible doesn't teach that the Bible says
it happens at the end and even then we
have to understand why is God using fire
is God angry is God trying to make this
painful for what is he doing and does he
do this for all eternity so come on
we're going to get there but first
before we I got I got one more major
point to cover but before we do that we
need to talk about Lazarus and the rich
man so is this a
contradiction is this a
contradiction Luke 16:19 there was a
certain rich man who clothed in Pur who
which was clothed in purple and fine
linen and fared sumptuously every day
and there was a certain beggar named
Lazarus which laid at which was laid at
his gate full of sores and he desired to
be fed with the crumbs which fell from
the rich man's table moreover the dogs
came and licked his sores and it came to
pass that the beggar died and was
carried by the Angels into Abraham's
bosom the rich man also died and was
buried and in hell he lifted up his eyes
and being in torment he see he sees
Abraham a far off and Lazarus in his
bosom and he cried and said Father
Abraham have mercy on me and send
Lazarus that he may dip the tip of his
finger in water and cool my tongue for I
am tormented in this flame but Abraham
said Son remember that thou in thy
lifetime receiveth thy good things and
likewise Lazarus evil things but now he
is comforted and thou are tormented and
beside all this between us and you there
is a great Gulf fixed that they which
would pass from hence to you cannot
neither can they pass to
wow I accidentally muted my bad I'm not
going to read that again but y'all see
the parable
right y'all see the
parable y'all see the story I should say
let me just share something with you
very
quickly y'all can can y'all hear
me y'all should be able to hear
me yes put a one in the
chat all right okay
good okay so I want you to not this so
the parable is Luke 16 the story is in
Luke 16 if you go back to Luke 10 you
have the parable of the Good Samaritan
Luke 12 the parable of the bridge fool
Luke 13 the parable of the Fig Tree and
the parable of the Mustard Seed Luke 14
the parable of the wedding feast and
then the great banquet Luke 15 the
parable of the lost sheep the Lost coin
and the prodigal Sun Luke 16 the parable
of this of the dishonest manager and
then the story of the rich man and
Lazarus and then Luke 18 the parable of
the persistent Widow and then the
parable of the Pharisee and the tax
collector and what I'm basically saying
to you is that The Story of Lazarus and
the rich man is a parable in the midst
of a bunch of Parables and if it is a
parable then the parable is not
something to be taken literally the
parable is designed to teach a
story if we take the Story of Lazarus
and the rich man literally then when the
Dead die they go to Abraham's bosom his
belly when the Dead die heaven and hell
are close enough for the righteous and
the wicked to talk with each
other this story would be really
outlandish by the fact that of all the
millions of people that are alive in
Hell supposedly and all the millions of
people that are alive in heaven the this
rich man happens to just see Lazarus
nobody else no one else can be sent hey
millions of people the only person I
knew when I was alive is Lazarus so let
me talk to Lazarus it's a parable
meaning it's not a story that was to be
taken literally Jesus is using this as
an illustration to teach
something not only that the request is
ludicrous give me a
tip a a drop of water to cool my tongue
that doesn't make any
sense here's a question if this is a
parable which it is what is the lesson
that is being taught the lesson being
taught is not
that when you go to heaven or when you
go to hell people want to help each
other but they can't because there's
this Great Gulf between them
no this rich man represented the Jewish
Nation had everything at their
fingertips and then this beggar
who dies outside the gates of the city
of the Rich Man Of The House of the rich
man who dies outside the they treated
him as a beggar someone poor someone who
had not a place to lay his head they
treated him with
disdain he dies outside the gates of the
House of the rich man and
then he is taken to the father's bosom
do y'all want to know who this Lazarus
is it's none other than Jesus
yo in the parable they're like hey send
Lazarus back from the dead and my
brothers will believe and the response
comes back if your brothers reject the
word of God even if one were raised from
the dead even if one were raised from
the dead they still wouldn't believe was
Jesus raised from the
dead how did the Pharisees and Sadducees
respond to him being raised from the
dead we still not
believing Jesus was telling a parable
about the future of his own people in
relation to
himself not that when the Dead die they
go to a place where they have knowledge
and understanding and they can talk to
each other that would reject everything
that the old Testament teaches and the
New Testament okay so now that we've got
that out the way we got one more thing
to cover which is this the duration and
the source of the fire and this is kind
of the grand finale of this message all
right the Bible says here in Psalm 37
verse2 but the wicked Shall Perish and
the enemies of the Lord shall be as the
fat of the Lambs they shall consume into
smoke shall they consume away we're told
here that the wicked will be consumed
not that they endure but that will be
consumed into smoke shall they be
consumed away into
nothingness that's what the text
says the question is how are they
consumed the answer is watch this you
guys Hebrews 12:29 says for our God is a
consuming fire our God is a
consuming fire
God everyone is a fire a consuming fire
and it is this consuming fire in fact
let me show you something
here in the Book of Ezekiel chapter one
there's the description of
Jesus in verse 26 it says above the
firmament that was over their heads was
the likeness of a throne and the
appearance of of a sapphire stone and
upon the likeness of the throne was the
likeness of the S of the appearance of a
man above upon it and I saw as has the
color of amber and the appearance of
fire round about within it from the
appearance of his loins even upward and
from the appearance of his loins even
downward I saw as it were the appearance
of fire and it had brightness round
about it I want you to understand
something here beloved that Jesus
himself is a consuming fire put a one in
the chat if you get what if you
understand what I just said Jesus
himself is a
consuming fire
are you with
me follow me here why is this
significant why am I talking about God
being a consuming fire and Jesus a
consuming fire uh in the Bible the Bible
says this remember remember what we just
saw about the appearance of Jesus and
who God is in Genesis 1:26 the Bible
says and God said let us make man in our
image and after our likeness stop right
there if man was made in God's image and
his
likeness then that tells
me that man was made with the ability to
stand in the presence of
God without being consumed by that fire
put a one in the chat if you understand
what I just
said God made man with the ability to
stand in his presence without being
consumed by that fire in fact in Psalm
104:1 the Bible says bless the Lord oh
my soul oh Lord my God Thou Art great
very great thou art clothed with honor
and Majesty who cover thyself with light
as with a garment now that's very
interesting God covers himself with
light as with a
garment in verse 104 it says who maketh
his angels spirits and his Ministers of
flaming fire that word ministers means
worshippers think about this for a
moment when God made Adam and
Eve he covered them in his righteousness
and if his righteousness is like a robe
of light and I want you to understand
light is fire you
guys light is
fire the light of God is the fire of God
so when Adam and Eve were created and
created in the likeness of God they were
covered they were covered in the light
of God in the righteousness of God and
and what's interesting is that when Adam
and Eve sinned watch this when Adam and
Eve sinned the Bible says and the eyes
of them both were open and they knew
that they were naked why are they all of
a sudden
naked because their light is
gone h
their light is
gone see now they're now they're
dwelling in
darkness now they're dwelling in
darkness so that when the Bible says
that when God comes to them in the
garden watch this when God comes to them
in the garden the Bible says they heard
the voice of the Lord God Walking In The
Garden in the cool of the day in the
cool of the day and Adam and his wife
hid themselves from the presence of the
Lord now hold on what did we see about
the presence of the Lord earlier the
presence of the Lord what is
that the presence of the Lord is
fire the presence of the Lord is
glory and so now now that they are naked
now that they have lost their light
their covering of righteousness the
Bible says when God comes in the garden
they are now afraid of the
fire they are now afraid of the
fire now watch this
what is God's goal in the Plan of
Salvation God's goal in the Plan of
Salvation y'all is to get man back to
the place where they are
red with that light here here here let
me show you Revelation 79 after this I
beheld in low a great multitude which no
man could number of all Nations kindreds
tongues and people stood Before the
Throne and before the lamb clothed with
white
robes now
that same word used for white robes that
same word this is what the righteous
will be wearing in heaven white robes
that same word here's how it's described
in Mark 9:2 after six days Jesus taketh
him take him take with him Peter and
James and John and leaded them up into a
high mountain apart by themselves and he
was transfigured before them and his
reignment became
shining exceeding white as snow so as no
Fuller on Earth can whiten
them it was a robe of light
y'all a robe of
light a robe of
fire in heaven beloved listen carefully
to me in heaven the righteous will be on
fire but it won't matter because they're
not being
burned the righteous will be able to
stand in the presence of God and not be
consumed the plan of God is to make is
to remake man so that he can stand in
the Everlasting fire of God without
being
consumed come on y'all let let me let me
help you understand this you see in the
the Bible fire is symbolic of something
according to Song of Solomon Chapter 8:6
the Bible says set me as a seal upon
thine heart as a seal upon thine arm for
love is strong as death jealousy is as
cruel as the grave the CES thereof are
CS of fire which has a most vem love or
vem flame many Waters cannot quench love
many Waters cannot quench love beloved
in the Bible fire God's fire is symbolic
of his love in other words fire is the
love language of
heaven and what God wants to do in the
Plan of Salvation is to make man again
so that he can stand in the fiery
presence of God and not be consumed
hence Exodus 3:1 the Bible says now
Moses kept the flock of Jethro his
father-in-law the priest of Midian he
led the flock to the backside of the of
the desert and came to the Mountain of
God even to Horeb and the angel of the
Lord appeared unto him in a flame of
fire out of the midst of a bush and he
looked and behold the bush burned with
fire and the Bush was not
consumed and Moses said I will turn
aside now and see this great sight why
the bush is not
burnt this was a mystery to Moses what
is the meaning of this bush that is that
is in the midst of fire but is not being
consumed and beloved I tell you God was
in that symbol seeking to demonstrate to
Moses and to
mankind this is my goal for
mankind to bring man to the place where
he can dwell in my presence again and
not be consumed but to do that I've got
to remove Sin from him to do that I've
got to do something in man that will
transform him so that he can stand in my
presence and guess what stand with me
watch this Revelation 52 I saw as that
wor a sea of glass mingle with fire and
them that had gotten the victory over
the Beast and over his image and over
his Mark and over the number of his name
St stand on the sea of glass having the
hearts of God beloved in order for us to
stand on the sea of glass mingle with
fire we have to be
fireproof let me say it again we must be
fireproof we must be able to stand in
the presence of God without being
consumed and now let me remind you of
the famous story of Shadrach m ja and
Abednego who were standing in the
Babylonian Empire who were asked to bow
down before an image and they were
threatened with fire they were
threatened with fire and the Bible says
because of their faithfulness H H
Nebuchadnezzar got angry and took them
bound them and threw them into the fire
now watch this Daniel 3:20 and he
commanded the most mighty men that were
in his army to bind Shadrach Meshach and
Abednego and to cast them into the
burning fiery furnace then these men
were Bound in their coats and holes and
and hats and other garments and were
cast into the midst of the burning fiery
furnace therefore because the king's
commandment was urgent and the furnace
exceeding hot the flame of the fire slew
the men that took up Shadrach Meshach
and Abednego they were not
fireproof they were slain by the fire
but what happened to Shadrach mesach and
Abednego these three men fell down in
the midst of the burning fiery furnace
then Nebuchadnezzar the King was
astonied and Rose up in haste and spake
and said unto his counselors did not we
cast three men Bound in the midst of the
fire they answered and said unto the
king true O King he answered and said lo
I see four men loose walking in the
midst of the fire and they have no hurt
and the form of the fourth is like the
Son of God do y'all catch
this these three Hebrews were fireproof
why because because they knew the fourth
man who was a man of fire
himself so it is Beloved the devil has
has flipped this truth and made it a
horrendous
lie the devil says it's the wicked that
will burn forever but the Bible says
something very different the Bible tells
us in Isaiah 33 and verse4 the sinners
in Zion are afraid fearfulness has pris
the Hypocrites who among us shall dwell
with the devouring fire who among us
shall dwell with Everlasting burnings he
that walketh righteously and speaketh
uprightly he that despiseth the gain of
the oppression he that shaketh his hands
from holding of bribes that stoppeth his
ears from hearing of blood and shth his
eyes from seeing evil he shall dwell on
high H do you know do you know what this
verse is telling us that it's the
righteous that will burn forever not the
Wicked the wicked cannot burn forever
because they are not
fireproof they cannot stand in the
presence of God without being consumed
that fire that destroys the Wicked at
the end of time is none other than the
fire of
God it is the presence of God that's why
the Bible says that that the wicked
shall be destroyed in the presence of
the lamb and in the presence of God it's
because it's the fire of God that
destroys the wicked that's why the Bible
describes it as Eternal fire it's not
that the wicked burn forever it's that
the fire is eternal why because that
fire is
God Jude 17 even as Sodom and Gomorrah
the cities about them in like manner
giving themselves over the fornication
and going after strange flesh are set
forth for an example suffering the
Vengeance of Eternal
fire it is
God it is God himself that was the
Eternal fire that destroyed Sodom and
Gomorrah Sodom and Gomorrah is not
burning now but the fire that destroyed
it is still burning why because that
fire is God it's the fire that that is
eternal not the wicked beloved again
Matthew 25:41 then shall he say unto
them on the left hand depart from ye
cursed into Everlasting fire prepared
for the devil and his angels it's the
fire that is Everlasting not the Wicked
the wicked are not
Everlasting why are the wicked not
Everlasting because the wicked are not
fireproof the wicked cannot live in
heaven because heaven is a city of fire
Heaven is a place of fire god is a
consuming fire his throne is a Throne of
Fire the angels are spirits of fire and
so in order to be in heaven you need to
be
fireproof notice with me Revelation 20
we're almost done beloved we got just a
few more we're almost done Revelation
20:10 the Bible says and the devil that
deceiveth them were cast into the lake
of fire and brimstone where the Beast
and the false prophet are and shall be
tormented day and night forever and ever
now you're like all right Pastor you
just lost me because the Bible clearly
says here that Satan is tormented day
and night forever and ever let me break
this down for you
please notice with me notice with me uh
Exodus
21:6 because I want you to see here that
the term forever and ever does not mean
absolutely forever and ever let me break
it down for you please Exodus 21:6 then
his master speaking about a person who
wanted to serve his Master like you know
for the rest of his life here's what it
says then his master shall bring him
unto the judges and he shall bring him
to the door or onto the door post and
his master shall bore his air through
with an all and he shall serve him
forever now let me ask a
question to serve a person's Master
forever what does that mean does that
mean throughout all eternity or does
that mean as long as the person shall
live yeah as long as a person shall live
when you say to your kids I love you
forever I will always love you what does
that mean I will love you as long as I
live in Exodus 30: 211 so shall they
watch talking about the priest shall
wash their hands and their feet that
they die not it shall be a statute for
them forever and ever hold on if the
temple was
destroyed if the temple was destroyed
and the priesthood brought to an end how
in the world does this forever and ever
not just mean as long as the system
stood in
place very good y'all forever and ever
means until death in Psalm
145:2 the Bible says every day will I
bless thee and I will praise thy name
forever and ever can someone praise God
forever and ever no here's why because
the same psalmist writes the dead praise
not the Lord neither any that go down
into silence but we will bless the Lord
from this time forth and forever more
praise the Lord in other words when he
says I'm going to praise the Lord
forever and ever he's meaning as long as
I live so when the Bible says that that
that Satan will be tormented forever and
ever it means that he's going to be
tormented for a long time but that it's
eventually gonna come to an end how do
we know this how do we know this to be
the case very simple you guys in Ezekiel
28:18 speaking of Lucifer the Bible says
Thou Hast defy thy sanctuaries by the
multitude of thine iniquity by the
iniquity of thy traffic therefore I
bring forth a fire from the midst of
thee it shall devour
thee what happens when something's
devoured it comes to an end I will bring
thee to ashes Satan is going to become
ashes
y'all I will bring Thee the ashes upon
the earth and the sight of all them that
behold thee upon the Earth in the sight
of all them that behold thee all they
that Know Thee among the people shall be
astonished at thee thou shall be a a
terror and never shalt thou be anym
somebody needs to say praise God Satan
is going to cease to
exist listen to me there's not going to
be some place off in the corner of the
universe where the wicked are being
tormented throughout all eternity no if
that was the case sin will be
eternalized and God is not going to
eternalize sin he is out to destroy sin
and
sinners
forever so when the Bible talks about
the consequences of sin you know like uh
Eternal um Daniel 12 puts it some shall
rise to Everlasting contempt it's not
that they will be in contempt forever
and ever it's the result of that
contempt in other words you're G to die
you're never going to come back to life
and this is going to be final
in the first death everybody comes back
to life everybody has a resurrection in
the second death there is no return from
it you're dead forever you're not living
forever you're dead forever how do we
know this the Bible says whosoever hath
hateth his brother is a murderer and you
know that no murderer has eternal life
abiding in
him listen
y'all if I have eternal life right now
and you tried to kill me what would
happen What would happen if I had
eternal life right now and you're like
I'm gonna I'm gonna stab you and you try
to stab me if I have eternal life right
now like actual eternal life would I
die no eternal life equals the inability
to
die did y'all catch that eternal life
means I am no longer subject to
death I can be sick but I have eternal
life I can I can probably live in a
miserable condition but I can't
die so if you have eternal life you
cannot be subject to
death so if the Bible says that no
murderer has eternal life abiding in him
then it means he's subject to death and
beloved listen to me death is not an
eternal state of living miserably that's
not
death death is the opposite of
life now you can live life miserably
that's not death death is the cessation
of life so when the Bible talks about
the second death being the wicked cast
into the lake of fire the fire is going
to be final in its
work meaning you will be brought to
death and never rise
again and if the Bible tells us that no
murderer has eternal life abiding in him
and John 8:44 says you are of your
father the devil and the lust of your
father he will do you will do he was a
murderer from the beginning then you
know beloved that the devil does not
have eternal life and if the devil
doesn't have eternal life the fires must
bring him to
death he must die hence this is not a
contradiction between Revelation 20 he
will be tormented day and night forever
and ever and he will cease to exist what
the what we what we need to understand
is that he will be tormented nonstop in
the
fire he will be tormented nonstop in the
fire
until give me one second here give me
one second something just popped up uh
popped up on my screen
okay all right so he will be tormented
in fire
until he is brought to nothingness
absolutely consumed and he will cease to
be forever and
ever praise
God okay here's my closing thought
y'all in John 3:14 G the Bible says as
Moses lifted up the serpent in the
wilderness even so must the son of man
be lifted up that whosoever believeth in
him should not perish but have
everlasting life I want you to see here
that there's a difference between perish
and everlasting life if you have
everlasting life you can't
perish if you don't have everlasting
life you're going to
perish the wages of sin is death would
you all agree with
that if the wages of sin is death it's
either the Wes of sin is death or it's
eternal torment it can't be both
because death and eternal torment are
two different things so either the Wes
of sin is death or it is eternal torment
now if the wagees of sin is death then
Jesus Paid that because he
died and whoever will can be saved all
they got to do is accept Jesus's death
on their behalf but if the wages of sin
is eternal torment then guess what y'all
Jesus didn't pay
that he wasn't eternally tormented wow
he wasn't eternally tormented Ed and if
he wasn't eternally tormented then he
didn't pay the penalty for sin and if he
didn't pay the penalty for sin then
everybody's
lost do y'all
see therefore the very fact of Jesus's
death and he was only dead for three
days shows that he did not suffer
Eternal he wasn't tormented eternally
meaning the Wes of sin cannot be eternal
torment if the Wes of sin is eternal
etal torment everybody's loss because
Jesus did not pay that
penalty his suffering was infinite but
it was not
Eternal
okay it was Jesus's death on the cross
that saves Us From Hell the
grave but there's something else Jesus
did to save
us from
fire in Matthew
11 John the Baptist said I indeed
baptize you with water into repentance
but he that cometh after me is mightier
than I whose shoes I'm not worthy to
Bear he shall baptize you with the Holy
Ghost and with
fire I need you to understand
this that in order to escape the fire of
God's Presence at the end of time we
must first be baptized with the fire of
his presence
now his death on the cross redeems us
from the
grave his baptism at the
Jordan saves us from the second
death if that's not beautiful
y'all if that if that does not
demonstrate the love of
God when the wicked are destroyed by the
fire of
God it is because of the love of God God
knows that if the wicked were to go into
heaven it would be eternal torment for
them and God loves too much to eternally
to torment Forever The Wicked so what
does he
do I like to put it this way that God
with his great big arms of fire is going
to embrace
the
wicked one last time and in that
embrace the wicked will feel what it
would be like to live in the presence of
a holy
God and in that moment the wicked will
understand that heaven would be hell for
them and God does the merciful thing
after they have paid for all of their
sins
God will allow them to become Ashes to
cease to exist forever and
ever and my appeal to you
today is to respond to God's amazing
plan to
Ransom you from the grave and to save
you from that second death which means I
have to accept what he did for me at the
cross that opens the gate of hell and
being baptized by his spirit and by his
presence It prepares me to stand in his
presence without being
consumed put a one in the chat if that's
what you want one in the chat
Lord help me to accept your sacrifice on
my behalf and help me to be baptized
with the fire of your presence so I can
stand in your presence and not be
consumed beloved I pray that this
teaching today this is the first time
you're hearing this today I pray that it
has
revolutionized your thoughts of the
character of
God Embrace him
now get on fire now so that when he
comes again you can stand in his
presence and not be afraid not be
consumed and be covered in the light of
his glory pray with me Heavenly Father
we thank you for
speaking we thank you for shedding light
on this subject Lord as we continue to
build this truth series I pray that
those who understand this will share
this with as many as they can and those
who are hearing this for the first time
will have their minds
blown that they will see you in a new
light and a new way and that the trauma
the the the the the mental anguish of
seeing you in a light that is not like
it is the devil who would do something
like that the devil that would torment
in such ways like that that's not who
you are and yes while the wicked do must
suffer and while they have to pay for
their sins done in the flesh
Lord it is unlike you to torment h h h
to to to
torture to go above and beyond what a
just sentence even for the wicked
is so Lord please
vindicate may your character be
Vindicated through this teaching thank
you Lord for being a god of
love for doing everything you can to
save as many as you can from hell and
from
Hellfire may we respond to your grace
and your love is our prayer in Jesus
name amen and amen I want to invite you
to alter live you'll see it there on the
screen for those of you who would like
to discuss either the Sabbath school or
the message today please feel free to
join us fellowship with us and may God
bless you and may God set your hearts on
fire amen